David **Ibáñez**



23 years old student of Engineering in Computer Science at University of Chile, and self-taught developer, is looking for an intership starting in January. Zealous about software engineering from an early age, currently interested in software development, static analysis, proof assistants and education.

Education

Engineering in Computer Science

Mar 2020 - Present

Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences, University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

Professional Experience

14 Software Developer t14 Consulting

Feb 2023 - Present

Remote work

- Design and implementation of custom made software, primarly in Java.
- FACT: Design and implementation of batched requests for high throughput in Apache Camel.
- · Levers NetChange: Optimization of Snowflake requests, analyze and transform SQL queries to minimize DB requests.

Java Apache Camel Apache Kafka Snowflake AWS Spring Gradle



Supervized Project

Ago 2024 - Dec 2024

Santiago, Chile

- Design of abstractions for including gradual typing techniques into static analyses with abstract interpretation.
- · Helping into the design, and implementation, of analyses on top of the developed abstractions.
- · Code done in Scala using the framework Sturdy
- Working under the supervision of Matías Toro and Éric Tanter.

Scala Static Analysis



Teaching Assistant

Mar 2024 - Dec 2024

Santiago, Chile

• CC4101 Programming Languages: Grading evaluations.



Teaching Assistant

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

Santiago, Chile

• CC4005 Competitive Programming: Giving lessons, grading, and designing evaluations

C/C++ GDB



Full-Stack Intern Simple Data Corp.

Summer 2019

Santiago, Chile

- · Design and implementation of new features to existing dynamic forms module.
- Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter 3, JQuery, RabbitMQ, Postman, Linux tools.

Projects & Associations

Treasurer & IT Manager

2023

Student Council of the Department of Computer Science (CaDCC)

Santiago, Chile

- Managing the organization founds and public founds provided by the department.
- · Managing CaDCC's own server and its services.

Archievements

Best Application, Verifiable Randomness Hackathon by Laboratory of Applied 2024 Santiago, Chile Cryptography and Cybersecurity (CLCERT) Place 21/105, International Collegiate Programming Contest South America/South Finals 2022 Coquimbo, Chile 2021 Place 30/63, International Collegiate Programming Contest South America/South Finals Valparaíso, Chile Place 11/153, Chilean Olympiads of Informatics (OCI) Santiago, Chile

Skills.

Languages English | Spanish

Java, Groovy, Scala | C/C++ | OCaml, F#, F* | Python Programming

Spring | DJango | Apache Camel | Sturdy Frameworks

Miscellaneous Linux power user | Formal Language Semantics | Static Analysis | Typst | Coq | Git

Personal Interests Reading | Videogames | Anime | Programming Languages

David Ibáñez Curriculum vitae